A Finding Aid to the Bernard Harper Friedman papers,1926-2011, bulk 1943-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.friebern
Archives of American Art
Bernard Harper Friedman papers
bulk 1943-2010
1926-2011
AAA.friebern
Archives of American Art
30.6 Linear feet
The papers of writer, art critic and collector Bernard Harper Friedman, 1926-2011, bulk 1943-2010, measure 30.6 linear feet. Extensive professional and personal correspondence, 41 diaries, a large number of his published and unpublished writings, and subject files document Friedman's career as a writer, relationships with cultural institutions and art world figures, and his personal life. Also included are biographical materials, interviews, printed material, 5 scrapbooks and photographs.
Friedman, B. H. (Bernard Harper), 1926-2011
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Bernard Harper Friedman papers were donated to the Archives of American Art in 2012 by his daughter, Daisy Friedman.
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is ACCESS RESTRICTED; written permission is required. Use of original materials requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1926-2011 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1946-2011 (Boxes 1-15; 14.7 linear feet)
Series 3: Interviews, 1969-2001 (Box 15; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Writings, 1940s-2010 (Boxes 16-23; 8 linear feet)
Series 5: Diaries, 1948-1993 (Boxes 24-25; 1.75 linear feet)
Series 6: Subject Files, 1940-2010 (Boxes 25-30; 4.45 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1954-2010 (Box 30-31; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1960-2006 (Boxes 30-32; 0.8 lilnear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1950s-2008 (Box 30; 0.4 linear feet)
Scope and Contents note
The papers of writer, art critic and collector Bernard Harper Friedman, 1926-2011, bulk 1943-2010, measure 30.6 linear feet. Extensive professional and personal correspondence, 41 diaries, a large number of his published and unpublished writings, and subject files document Friedman's career as a writer, relationships with cultural institutions and art world figures, and his personal life. Also included are biographical materials, interviews, 5 scrapbooks, and photographs.
Biographical materials include educational records, documentation of Friedman's World War II service in the U.S. Navy, and birth, marriage, and death certificates.
Correspondence is with friends, family, artists, art world figures and institutions, writers, publishers, and literary agents. Among the correspondents are: John I. H. Baur, Harry Bertoia, Flora Biddle, Norman Bluhm, James Brooks, Fritz Bultman, Leo Castelli, William N. Copley, Jim Dine, Helen Frankenthaler, Brendan Gill, Robert Goodnough, Cleve and Francine Gray, Howard Kanovitz, Grace Knowlton, Stanley Kunitz, Conrad Marca-Relli, Mercedes Matter, Fred W. McDarrah, Rory McEwen, Robert Motherwell, Arnold Newman, Barnett Newman, Dorothy Norman, Alfonso Ossorio, Provincetown Fine Arts Work Center, Robert Richenburg, Barney Rosset, Philip Roth, Judith Rothschild, Irving Sandler, Salvatore Scarpitta, Jon Schueler, Sidney Simon, David Slivka, Clyfford Still, Myron Stout, Calvin Tompkins, and David Windham.
There are transcripts of interviews with B. H. Friedman, his daughter and wife conducted by the Yale University School of Medicine's "Adult Development Study," and 2 recordings of interviews with Friedman for radio broadcast.
Writings by Friedman include manuscripts of novels, short stories, plays, articles, monographs, and art criticism, some published versions of his work, and a variety of notes. Also found are recordings of lectures by B. H. Friedman and panel discussions in which he participated. Other authors represented are John Cage, W. B. Henry, and Jon Schueler. Friedman's diaries, 1948-1993 (41 volumes) record activities, thoughts, and events.
Subject files compiled by Friedman reflect professional and personal interests, activities, and projects. Many concern publicity for published writings or efforts to find publishers. Especially well documented is his interest in Jackson Pollock, Timothy Leary, and Alfonso Ossorio, and his affiliation with the Whitney Museum of American Art.
The majority of printed material is about or mentions Friedman. Five scrapbooks consist mainly of printed material.
Most photographs are of B. H. and Abby Friedman, their family, and friends. Among the individuals pictured are: Elise Asher, Cary and Norman Bluhm, Sandy Friedman, Joellen Hall, Doug Huebler, Howard Kanowitz, Stanley Kunitz, Lee Krasner, Sheridan Lloyd, Barnett and Annalee Newman, Alfonso Ossorio, Magda Salvesen, Salvatore Scarpitta, John Schueler, and Myron Stout. A photograph album records scenes from a 1979 performance of Whispers, a stage adaptation by Alan Wynroth from Friedman's novel of the same title.
Biographical/Historical note
Bernard Harper Friedman (1926-2011), a writer best known as the author of the first biography of Jackson Pollock, was also an art critic and art collector involved in the cultural life of New York City.
Bernard Harper Friedman, known professionally as B. H. Friedman, was called Bob by family and friends. After interrupting his studies at Cornell University to serve in the U.S. Navy during World War II, he graduated in 1948 with a degree in English. Friedman and his new bride, fellow student Abby G. Noselson (1926-2003), returned home to New York City and he began a real estate career in his uncles' firm, Uris Buildings Corporation. While a businessman, Friedman spent much of his spare time writing. He produced fiction, plays, and criticism; Friedman's articles on art, literature and music appeared in a wide variety of periodicals. During this period, Friedman also pursued his interests in jazz, collecting abstract art, and psychedelic drug experiences with Timothy Leary.
His first published novel, Circles, about the Abstract Expressionist milieu, appeared in 1962. A year later, B. H. Friedman became a full-time writer. For nearly 20 years, he divided his time between New York City and Provincetown, Massachusetts, where he was affiliated with the Fine Arts Work Center as a director and consultant. During this period, he published several novels and two biographies: Jackson Pollock: Energy Made Visible and Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, written with Flora Biddle. More novels and short story collections were published, and staged readings of seven plays were presented between 1987 and 2007. Tripping, a memoir of using psychedlics with Timothy Leary, appeared in 2006.
A founding member of Fiction Collective, a nonprofit publishing group run by and for writers, Friedman was also a member of several national writers' organizations. He served as a trustee of the Whitney Musuem of American Art, 1961-1968, and then as honorary trustee. B. H. Friedman died from complications of pneumonia on January 4, 2011 in New York City.
Related Archival Materials note
Also available is an oral history interview with Bernard Harper Friedman, 1972 November 10, conducted by Paul Cummings for the Archives of American Art.
Asher, Elise, 1914-; Baur, John I. H., (John Ireland Howe), 1909-1987; Bertoia, Harry; Biddle, Flora Miller; Bluhm, Norman, 1921-1999; Brooks, James, 1906-; Bultman, Fritz; Cage, John, 1912-1992; Castelli, Leo; Copley, William Nelson, 1919-1996; Dine, Jim, 1935-; Frankenthaler, Helen, 1928-2011; Gill, Brendan, 1914-1997; Goodnough, Robert, 1917-; Gray, Cleve; Gray, Francine du Plessix; Hall, Joellen; Huebler, Douglas; Kanovitz, Howard; Knowlton, Grace, 1932-; Krasner, Lee, 1908-; Kunitz, Stanley, 1905-; Leary, Timothy; Marca-Relli, Conrad, 1913-; Matter, Mercedes; McDarrah, Fred W., 1926-2007; McEwen, Rory, 1932-; Motherwell, Robert; Newman, Arnold, 1918-2006; Newman, Barnett, 1905-1970; Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997; Ossorio, Alfonso, 1916-; Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956; Provincetown Fine Arts Work Center.; Richenburg, Robert; Rosset, Barney; Roth, Philip; Rothschild, Judith; Salvesen, Magda; Sandler, Irving, 1925-; Scarpitta, Salvatore, 1919-2007; Schueler, Jon, 1916-; Simon, Sidney, 1917-1997; Slivka, David, 1913-; Still, Clyfford, 1904-1980; Stout, Myron, 1908-1987; Whitney Museum of American Art.; Art critics--New York (State)--New York; Art--Collectors and collecting--New York (State)--New York; Authors--New York (State)--New York; Diaries; Interviews; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sound recordings; Transcripts
- Biographical Materials, 1926-2011; Series 1; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Certificates record the 1926 births of Bernard Harper Friedman and Abby G. Noselson, their marriage in 1948 (with guest list), and his death in 2011. Educational records are from Cornell University. The self portraits are two small caricatures drawn in ink, one is a photocopy.
  Arrangement note
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Address Book, circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Notes and Curriculum Vitae, circa 1968-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1926-2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Educational Records, 1948-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Military Records, 1944-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Obituaries, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Passport, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Self-portraits, 1981; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1946-2011; Series 2; 14.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-15
  Friedman's correspondence is both professional and personal in nature, occasionally combining both spheres. Many letters are addressed to Bob (as Friedman was known to family and friends). Some are addressed to the couple and a few are to Abby.
  This series is alphabetized by correspondent. Filing is inconsistent - some letters may be found under the correspondent's name while other portions of the exchanged are filed by business name. Folders for individual correspondents contain five or more letters. Correspondence with individuals or organizations represented by fewer than five letters is grouped alphabetically in folders titled "miscellaneous." Additional correspondence is found among the subject files (Series 6).
  - A, Miscellaneous, 1954-2008 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc, 1969-1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACA Galleries, 1982-2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Accent: The Journal of Leeds College of Art and School of Architecture, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Wayne, 1965-2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alexander, William, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alonso, Juan, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Althaus, Keith and Susan Baker, 1973-2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Altschul, Arthur, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Amaden, James P., 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Amburn, Ellis, 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Book Review, 1979-2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1970-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Heritage, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Anderson, Charles R., 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Anderson, Joanna, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Andrews, George, 1962-2010 (Box 1, Folder 26-30)
  - Antaeus, 1977-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Architectural Forum, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Arman, Yves, 1965-1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Art Dealers Association, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Art Digest, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Artforum, 1972-2008 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Art in America, 1955-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Art International, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - ARTnews, 1954-1996 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Arts Magazine, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Askoff, Louis S., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1960-1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Atlantic/Little, Brown and Company, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Aubi, Eileen, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Auchincloss, Louis S., 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Austin, Charles, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Authors Guild, Inc., 1965-2009 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Avon, 1954-1961 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1954-2008 (Box 1, Folder 50-53)
  - Bachner, Robert L. and Barbara, 1965-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baltzell, F. Digby, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Banks, Don, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Banks, Russell, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Barnes Foundation, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Barrie and Jenkins, Publishers, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bates, Harry, 1989-2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Barthelme, Frederick, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Baur, John I. H., 1968-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bayard, Jane, 1994-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BBC, 1987-2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Beaumont, Carol, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bellow, Saul and Keith Bottsford, 1961-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bendroth, Mark, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Benes, Barton, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Berger, Milton, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bergman, Charles, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bergman, Lewis, 1970-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bergman, Nicholas, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bernard, Joe, 1980-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bernhard, Robert A., 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bernhard, Willa, 1992-2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bernstein, Judith, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bertoia, Harry, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Biddle, Flora, undated; 1972-2011 (Box 2, Folder 26-36)
    Flora Biddle also corresponded with Friedman when she was named Flora Miller and Flora Irving.
  - Bishop, Alison Lurie, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Blackwell, Robin, 1995-2005 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Blinken, Donald, 1969-2005 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Bluhm, Norman and Cary, 1985-2007 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Bodine, Susan, 1981-2001 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bomb, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bonczek, James, 1980-2010 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Bonnell, Mary Lincoln, 1984-2003 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Bowen, Paul, 1984-2009 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Breslin, Edward F., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Brodsky, Robert, 1956-2010 (Box 2, Folder 47-49)
  - Broida, Edward R. and Alexa, 1986-2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Broida Musuem, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brooks, Ben, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brooks, James, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Barry, 2001-2009 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Brown, Mary Ward, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bruccoli, Matthew J., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bultman, Fritz and Jeanne, 1959-2009 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
  - Burlington Magazine, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Busa, Christopher, 1971-2011 (Box 3, Folder 13-18)
  - Busch, Ralph, 1968-2010 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Butscher, Ed, 1990-2010 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - C, Miscellaneous, 1956-2006 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
  - Cahn, Joshua, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Camargo Foundation, 1989-2005 (Box 3, Folder 25-28)
  - Camp, Jeffrey, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cantor, Jeffrey and Richard, 2005-2009 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Castelli, Leo, 1958-2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cecil, William A. V., 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Center for Book Arts, 1991-1996 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - The Century Association, 1978-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Chicago, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Choay, Françoise, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cohen, Martin, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Collier, Oscar, 1982-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Confrontations, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Connor, Russell, 1991-2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Connors, Peter, 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cook, Peter G., 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, Mark and Helene, 2002-2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Copley, William N., 1960-1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cordier and Ekstrom, Inc., 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Review, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Cornell University, 1962-2011 (Box 4, Folder 17-23)
  - Craft Horizons, 1957-1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Crooks, F. Corydon, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - The Crown Publishing Group, 1971-1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cummings, Paul, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Cunningham, Jere, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Curtis, Andrew, circa 2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - D, Miscellaneous, 1955-2007 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
  - Da Capo Press, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - The Dalton School, 1967-1979 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
  - Darrow, Whitney, Jr., 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Dawson, Fielding, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - The Dedalus Foundation, 2005-2009 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - De Groot, Pat, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Delorenzo, Anthony, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - de Menil, Christophe, 2006-2009 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Department of State, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dibble, David M., 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dictionary of American Biography, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dine, Jim and Nancy, 1966-2010 (Box 5, Folder 8-15)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1969-1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Drescher, Karl, 1973-1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Drummond Framing, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - E. P. Dutton, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Dwan Gallery, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - E, Miscellaneous, 1958-2006 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The East Hampton Star, 1972-2009 (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
  - Echaniz, G. M., 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ehrlich, Judith, 2002-2006 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Robert Elkon Gallery, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Ellis, Estelle, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Elman, Roy, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Andre Emmerich Gallery, 1962-1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Epoch, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Esman, Rosa and Aaron H., 1986-2010 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Esquire, 1985-2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Evans, Harold, 2006-2009 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Exact Change, 1998-2009 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
  - F, Miscellaneous, 1955-2010 (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Fabricant, Richard, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Fara, Henry, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 1960-1982 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Feder, Carrie, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Fiction Collective, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 42-45)
  - Fiction Collective, 1977-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
  - Fiction Collective - Coming Close, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fiction Collective - Between the Flags, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fiction Collective Two, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fingerhood, Shirley, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Finkle, David, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fisk, Heidi H., 1977-2010 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fleet Publishing Corporation, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Forte, Robert, 2001-2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Foster, Stephen C., 1998-2005 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fougeray, Inc., 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Frank, Jan, 1998-2009 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1956-2005 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Friedman, Aimee L., 1968-1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Friedman, Mr. and Mrs. Leonard (parents), 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Friedman, Marvin Ross, 1992-2005 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - G, Miscellaneous, 1955-2008 (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
  - Galich, Danica, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Garretson, Julia, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - George, Wayne, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Gill, Brendan, 1982-1998 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Girard, China, 2001-2010 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Gleichmann, Gabi and Lee, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Glimcher, Arnold and Mildred, 1986-2009 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Golightly, Bonnie, 1959-1970 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Goodman, James, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Goodnough, Robert, 1960-2008 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Goodrich, David, 2001-2009 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Goodrich, Lloyd, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Gordon, Joy L., 2004 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Gordon, Morris, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Gottlieb, Robert, 1973-1986 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Gould, Karolyn R., 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Governale, Richard, 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Grand Street, 1985-2004 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Gray, Cleve and Francine, 1960-2008 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Grove Press and Evergreen Review, 1956-1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Guest, Barbara [Higgins], 1959 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1959-2002 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Musuem, 1955-1997 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Guild Hall, 1983-2008 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - H, Miscellaneous, 1957-2007 (Box 6, Folder 48-50)
  - Halpern, Daniel, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Halpern, Susan, 1981-2010 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hamilton, George Heard, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hanna, William, 1964-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Harmon, Lily, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Harms, Robert, 2005-2011 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Harper and Row Publishers, Inc., 1969-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1959-2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Hart, Glyde, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Harvard University, 1978-2005 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hathaway, Baxter, 1952-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Havens, Susan Miller, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hayne, Patrick, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Drue Heinz Literary Prize, 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Heller, Ben, 1955-1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Heller, Ben - North Bay Associates, 1981-1987 (Box 7, Folder 17-19)
  - Henry, Barklie, 1968-2009; Includes 1 CD (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
  - Higgins, Douglas, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Hirsch, Donald and Polly, 1955-2008 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Hnida, Dorothy, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Hockstein, Betsy, 2000-2010 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Hoffield, Jeffrey, 1985-2003 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Hoffman, Jill, 1987-1999 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Horowitz, Glenn, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Horowitz, Michael, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Houston Contemporary Art Museum, 1958-1978 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Howard, Richard, 1957-2010 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Howell, Barbara, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - The Hudson Review, 1968-1998 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Huebler, Douglas, 1979-1997 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Huebner, Berna, 1994-2006 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Huey, Tom, 1975-1982 (Box 7, Folder 38-43)
  - Huey, Tom, 1983-2009 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
  - Hunter, Edys, 1969-1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hunter, Sam, 1956-1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Huppert, Florie, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hussey, Howard, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hutchings, Michael D., 1955-1999 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hyatte, Mary and Reggie, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - I, Miscellaneous, 1957-1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Irving, Flora and Michael, 1966-2007 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Flora Irving also corresponded with Friedman when she was named Flora Biddle and Flora Miller.
  - Irving, Linda, 2007-2009 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Iseman, Marjorie F., 1973-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - J, Miscellaneous, 1964-2008 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Jackson, Robert and Leslie, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jaffe, Harold, 1982-2008 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sidney Janis Sons Gallery, 1970-1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Jenkins, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1977-1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Jordan Volpe Gallery, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - K, Miscellaneous, 1968-2009 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
  - Kanovitz, Howard, 1956-2000 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Kardon, Janet, 2007-2009 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Katz, Steve, 1969-2010 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Katz, Vincent and Vivien, 2006-2009 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Kaufman, Pat, 1979-2010 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Kean, Ellen S., 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Kind, Phyllis, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - King, Basil, 1991-2003 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - King, Polly, 1982-2006 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Kings, Neltje, 1971-1994 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Kläger, Max, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Klauber, Jason, 2000-2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Klauber, Rick, 1975-2010 (Box 8, Folder 36-38)
  - Kline, Franz, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - M. Knoedler and Co., Inc., 1971-2009 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Knoll Associates, Inc., 1951-1955 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Knowlton, Grace, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 43)